## Ben Walls

benawalls@gmail.com - 509-710-4671 - chesthighwalls.com

# **Software Developer**

#### **Performance Profile**

2 years of back and front end experience, developing responsive websites. Collaborated in the creation of sites utilizing agile methods for project estimation. Designed using modern object oriented programming practices, and up to date techniques. Dedicated to problem solving, and able to follow through on a project to the end.

## **Skills**

- Experience building responsive websites with HTML, PHP 5, MySQL, JavaScript, CSS 3 and Sass
- Coded interactive websites and front end form validation with JQuery
- Programmed using Ruby, Java, and C#
- Wrote SQL queries and utilized joins, stored procedures, views, and functions
- Developed dynamic websites using Git as version control

## **Core Competencies**

- PHP 5	- HTML 5 / CSS 3
- JavaScript / JQuery	- Responsive Design
- ASP.Net / C#	- MySQL
- Foundation / Sass	- Ruby / Rails
- TDD	- Agile
- Git / GitHub	- Android Development / Java
- IOS Development /Swift	

### **Education**

Spokane Community Collage N 1810 Greene Street Spokane, WA 99217 2014 - 2016

- Two years in the Software development program
- Six certificates:
  - .Net Developer
  - Android Mobile Development
  - Computer Science
  - IOS Mobile Development
  - Web Design
  - Web Developer

## **Experience**

72<sup>nd</sup> Street Goodwill Tacoma, WA 2013 – 2014

- -Worked on the sales floor, and assisted customers
- -Stocked the shelves and kept them neat and tidy

Xerox/ACS Federal Way, WA 2012 – 2013

- -Worked as a customer service agent for Verizon Wireless, 3rd party
- -Assisted the customer with their bills, and corrected any errors
- -Troubleshooting on basic phone problems
- -Made sure the customer was on a plan that fit their needs
- -Provided the customer with information on new phones

Admiral Theatre Foundation Bremerton, WA 2009 – 2012

- -Worked as an on call stage hand and tech support
- -Worked with audio and lighting directors to set up and strike equipment for shows based on the acts requirements
- -Helped execute stage changes during shows
- -Assisted in handling hospitality
- -Worked directly under the Technical Director to assist in the maintenance and technical support for a windows small business server network with 14 work stations

#### **Accomplishments**

-Eagle Scout rank, the highest rank in the Boy Scouts